janeiredale.com 2018-11-23

# Privacy Policy | jane iredale

**Last updated August 2, 2017**

We at Iredale Mineral Cosmetics, Ltd. (“IMC”) are committed to protecting the privacy of our customers and visitors. This Privacy Notice describes the ways in which we collect, use, disclose and protect information about you in connection with your use of our website. When you use our website, you consent to our collection, use, and disclosure of information about you as described in this Privacy Notice.

#### 1\. Personal Information

“Personal information” is information by which you can be identified, such as your name, e-mail address, billing and mailing addresses, telephone number(s) and credit card number(s). When you provide personal information on our website, you are consenting to the way in which we collect, use and disclose your personal information, as described in this Privacy Notice.

We may collect personal information that you provide when you: 

  * Register with our website;
  * Make a purchase from our website;
  * Submit an entry in a contest or sweepstakes sponsored by us, respond to one of our surveys or participate in another feature of our website; or
  * Provide us with user content, ideas, information, user reviews, comments, feedback or other submissions.

We do not sell (or trade or rent) your personal information to third parties for their own marketing use. It’s possible, however, that we might acquire or merge with or be acquired by another company or that we might sell certain of our assets. In that event, we may disclose your personal information to another company, but that disclosure will be subject to the privacy notice that we then have in effect.

As do most Internet retailers, we engage third parties to perform functions on our behalf consistent with this Privacy Notice. We may provide your personal information to those third parties in order to allow them to perform their functions for us. Such information will be transmitted only through reasonably secure channels. We may also receive information from third party partners, such as marketing and demographic data, offline records and information from an advertiser about your experiences or interactions with them, which information we may combine with other information we receive from or about you.

#### 2\. Registration at Our Website

You have the option to register at our website, but no registration is required to browse our website. In order to register, you may be required to select a password and provide your name, e-mail address, and other information. You may edit any of your personal information at any time by logging into your account and following the "edit this information" link. If you do not create an account during a purchase, you may choose to create one later with the same email address you used for the purchase.

#### 3\. Purchases

When you make a purchase from janeiredale.com, we will collect the personal information needed to process and ship your order, including your name, phone number, e-mail address, shipping and billing addresses, and credit card number. We will use that information to process your order and to provide you with customer service.

We employ reasonable security measures to protect your personal and financial information. Credit card details supplied at checkout are transmitted directly to our payment provider over a secure connection (SSL). We do not save your full credit card number or security code on our servers. We keep only your card’s expiration date and the last four digits of your card number. This helps you and us to identify your saved credit card(s) when you call us or visit us online.

#### 4\. Participation in Contests, Sweepstakes, and Similar Promotions

Any sweepstake, contest or similar promotion made available through our website (or other of our platforms, such as social media) may be governed by rules specific to that contest, sweepstake or other promotion. By participating in any such sweepstake, contest or promotion, you agree to be governed by those rules, which may vary from the terms of this Privacy Notice. Please read carefully the applicable rules for any of our sweepstakes, contests or other promotions.

#### 5\. Product Reviews and other Postings You Make

Any personal information you submit as part of a product review or in connection with the submission of other postings you make (“User Content”) will be public information. This would include information such as your name or photo or likeness. We may use User Content for any purpose that we deem appropriate, including advertising, marketing, publicity and promotional activities, and we may choose whether to attribute such content to you when we use it. (Please refer to Section 6 of our Terms and Conditions of Website Use for a fuller description of how we may use content that you submit to us.)

#### 6\. Other Uses of Personal Information

In addition to the uses described above, we may use personal information to help us assess and improve our products and to notify you about products and services, sales and special events in which you might be interested. We may also internally use your personal information to improve the content and layout of our website and for our own marketing efforts.

If you register at or purchase products from our website, you may receive promotional e-mails from us. You may opt out of our mailing list during the registration or ordering process. In addition, if you have registered, you may log into your account at any time to opt in or opt out of our mailing list. You may opt out of our mailing list by using the supplied link in any of our e-mails.

#### 7\. Cookies and Other Technology

Our website uses “cookies” and “web beacons” (also known as clear GIF technology or “action tags”) to speed your navigation of the website, recognize you, and track your website usage. A “cookie” is a small data file that a site can send to your web browser, which may then be stored on your computer’s hard drive so that your computer is recognized when you return to the site. If you have registered with our website, these cookies may (a) let us know who you are, (b) be needed to enable you to access your account or other information, and (c) provide us with information that we may use to customize our website in accordance with your needs and preferences. Most Internet browsers are initially set to accept cookies. You can set your browser to notify you when you receive a cookie, and you can set your browser to reject cookies. If you elect not to accept cookies from our website, it may limit the options that our website provides for you.

Web beacons help to deliver cookies. They are used to help us determines whether and how many times a web page on our website has been viewed.

Like most standard website servers, we use log files. These include internet protocol (IP) addresses, browser type, internet service provider (ISP) addresses, referring/exit pages, platform type records, date/time stamp, and number-of-click tallies. We and third party vendors we work with may use this information to analyze trends, administer the website, track users’ movement in the aggregate, and gather broad demographic information for aggregate use. IP addresses, etc. are not linked to your personal information. Site visit information is used only in aggregate form to help enhance the overall user experience.

#### 8\. Third-party Online Advertising

We may also use third-party advertising companies to help tailor site content to users or to serve ads about goods or services that may be of interest to you. These companies may employ cookies and web beacons to collect data relating to your visit to our website in order to measure advertising effectiveness (such as which web pages are visited or what products are purchased and in what amount). The data these companies collect may be combined with data from other websites, mobile applications and sources. Any information that these third parties collect via cookies and web beacons is not linked to any personal information about you collected by us. If you would like more information about this practice and about your ability to opt-out of having this information used by those third-party advertisers participating in the National Advertising Initiative or the Digital Advertising Alliance, visit [http://networkadvertising.org](http://networkadvertising.org/) and <http://optout.aboutads.infor/#1/>. (Note that opting out of data collected by one browser will not necessarily opt you out of collection by other browsers or devices.)

#### 9\. Links to Third-Party Sites

For your convenience, our website may provide links to the websites of third parties. We do not assume any responsibility for the (a) content of, (b) technology implemented by, or (c) privacy practices of third-party sites. You use such sites at your own risk. You should review each site’s privacy notice and terms of use before you use or register on the site. Just because a link to a third-party site is available on our website does not mean we endorse that site. Because we do not control the availability and content of third-party sites, any concerns regarding any such website or the treatment of your personal information by such third-party should be directed to the particular third party website.

SEE SECTION 15 BELOW FOR IMPORTANT LIMITATIONS ON THE TERMS OF THIS SECTION 9.

#### 10\. Disclosures Required by Law

Although we are committed to protecting the privacy of the personal information of our customers and visitors, we may need to disclose personal information when required by law, governmental rule or regulation, subpoena or other judicial or administrative process.

#### 11\. Security of Personal Information

We maintain reasonable safeguards to protect against unauthorized access, use, modification and disclosure of personal information in our custody and control. Despite our efforts, we cannot guaranty that unauthorized access or use will never occur. It is important that you take steps to keep your information safe and secure. Choose an account password that is hard for others to guess and don’t reveal it to third parties. If you use a shared of public computer, do not opt to have your login ID or password remembered and be sure to log out of your account when you finish.

#### 12\. Changes to Privacy Notice

We may change our Privacy Notice from time to time. If we change or update this Privacy Notice, we will post the revised Privacy Notice on our website. Please check this page from time to time for any such revised Privacy Notice

#### 13\. No Collection of Information from Children

We do not collect or solicit information from anyone known to be under the age of 13. Should we discover that we have accidentally collected information from a child, we will promptly remove that information from our records.

#### 14\. California “Do Not Track” Disclosures

The California Online Privacy Protection Act of 2003, as amended in 2013, provides California residents with certain rights respecting the collection of personally identifiable information about them. Among those rights is the right to information about how a website responds to “do not track” signals from a browser. We do not currently recognize and process “do not track” signals. For more information about “do not track,” please visit [http://www.allaboutdnt.org](http://www.allaboutdnt.org/).

#### 15\. EXCLUSIONS AND LIMITATIONS; CONSUMER PROTECTION NOTICE

If you are a consumer, the provisions in this Privacy Notice are intended to be only as broad and inclusive as is permitted by the laws of your State of residence. If you are a New Jersey consumer, the terms of Section 9 do not limit or waive your rights as a consumer under New Jersey law and the provisions in this Privacy Notice are intended to be only as broad and inclusive as is permitted by the laws of the State of New Jersey. In any event, IMC reserves all rights, defenses and permissible limitations under the law of your State of residence.

#### 16\. Contacting us with Questions

Should you have any questions or concerns about this Privacy Notice, you can contact us at:

Iredale Mineral Cosmetics, Ltd.  
Attn: Website Privacy Notice  
50 Church Street  
Great Barrington, MA 01230
